MD SHAKIL AHAMED SHOHAG

CONTACT INFORMATION University of Jinan, No. 336, West Road of Nan Xinzhuang, Jinan

250022, Shandong, China

Homepage: https://shakilshohag.github.io/

+86 166 53155447 shakilshohag@gmail.com shakilshohag@mail.ujn.edu.cn

RESEARCH INTERESTS Computer vision, image processing, image feature fusion, deep learning and graph matching for establishing sparse feature correspondence of images. My thesis title is Graph Matching Algorithm for Image Matching Based on Feature Enhancement and Fusion. Previously, I have worked on wireless networking, mobile Ad-hoc network security and web security.

EDUCATION

University of Jinan, China

Sep 2018 - Present

Master's in Computer Science and Technology (Thesis ongoing)

CGPA: 4.23/5.00 | **Percentage:** 87.57 %

Advisor: Prof. Xiuyang Zhao

University of Development Alternative, Bangladesh

Jan 2007 - April 2011

BSc in Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering

(Completed) CGPA: 3.70/4.00

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Shohag, M. S. A., Hassan, M. U., Niu, D., Kong, X., Zhao, X., & Rahman, F. "Graph Based Image Matching Using the Fusion of Several Kinds of Features," In Proceedings of the 2019 4th International Conference on Multimedia Systems and Signal Processing (ICMSSP 2019). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 188-193. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3330393.3330421.
- [2] Shohag, M. S. A., Zhan, Y., Zhao, X., Hassan, M. U., Niu D. "Cross-graph reference structure based pruning and edge context information for graph matching," Multimedia Tools and Applications. (Under Review)
- [3] Hassan, M. U., Shohag, M. S. A., Niu, D., Shaukat, K., Zhang, M., Zhao, W., & Zhao, X. "A framework for the revision of large-scale image retrieval benchmarks," Proc. SPIE 11179, Eleventh International Conference on Digital Image Processing (ICDIP 2019), 111794D (14 August 2019); https://doi.org/10.1117/12.2539640.
- [4] Hassan, M. U., Niu, D., Zhao, X., Shohag, M. S. A., Ma, Y., & Zhang, M. "Salient Object Detection based on CNN Fusion of Two Types of Saliency Models," 2019 34th International Conference Vision Computing on Image and New Zealand doi:10.1109/ivcnz48456.2019.8960994.
- [5] Yasin, A. S. M., Haque, M. M., Naha, K., & Shohag, M. S. A. "Devise, Extend and Upgraded Algorithm of Gene Sequence for Local Alignment," International Journal of Engineering and Computer Science.
- [6] Haque, M. M., Kabir, R. A., & Ahamed, M. S. "Biometric Based Web Security Using Ridges of Finger," International Journal of Engineering and Computer Science, 2(08).

WORK **EXPERIENCE**

Shandong Provincial Key Laboratory of Network-Based Intelligent Computing, University of Jinan, China

Sep 2018 – Present

Research Assistant, Computer Vision and Deep Learning

- **Graph Matching**
- Image and Object Retrieval
- Machine Learning and Medical Imaging

Faculty of Engineering, University of Development Alternative, Jan 2012 – Sep 2016 **Bangladesh**

Lecturer

- **Teaching**
- Student Counseling
- Member of Academic Committee
- Member of Examination Committee
- Member of Seminar Committee
- Member of Tour Committee

Business Automation, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Aug 2017 – Aug 2018

Web Design and Development (Freelancer)

MD SHAKIL AHAMED SHOHAG

- Webpage Design: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Scripting: JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax
- Database Query: MySql (sql)
- Framework Specification: PHP-Laravel
- Manual Writing

VOLUNTEERY WORKS

International Student Dormitory, University of Jinan, China

Nov 2020 - Present

Assistant Administrator

- Inspection of the student rooms.
- Conducting meetings with international students
- Reporting to the dormitory admin.

International Student Dormitory, University of Jinan, China

Dec 2019 - May 2020

Help-fight pandemic worker

 Collecting and distributing food and emergency items for the residents during lockdown.

ADDITIONAL COURSES

- Coursera Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Coursera Improving DNN: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Coursera Structuring Machine Learning Projects
- Coursera Algorithmic Toolbox
- Coursera Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra
- Coursera Mathematics for Machine Learning: Multivariate Calculus
- **Techshop** Micro-Controller Based Embedded System Design & Robotics (Basic)
- **IICT**, **BUET** Embedded System Design & Development (Workshop)

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

- Fully Funded Chinese Government Scholarship for Master Studies (2018-2021)
- Academic performance based tuition fee waiver (50%) for entire undergraduate study, (2007-2011)
- 2nd position (departmental) at undergraduate level
- The best speaker, intra-departmental debate competition, UODA (2008)

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

Delivered Oral Presentation at 4th ICMSSP 2019, Guangzhou, China.

IKESENTATIO

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C/C++, MATLAB,

Public Library: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Caffe, OpenCV **Environments & IDE:** Linux, Windows, Visual Studio 2015

Languages & Scores: English (fluent), IELTS 8 (L-9, R-8, W-7, S-7); Mandarin (basic); Bangla

(native); Hindi & Urdu (fluent in verbal communication only)

INTERESTS

- Blogging, Vlogging
- Cardio: Cycling, Running, Swimming
- Sports: Badminton, Volleyball, Skating
- Books & Movies: Sci-Fi